-=字幕制作：电费喵.BluRay=-  使用、转载、编辑请注明来源
停下-啊
Stop-ah!
照明
Illumination!
# 我刚刚去了布鲁克林  现在来到了三角地#
# Yeah, I'm out that Brooklyn, now I'm down in Tribeca #
# 然后将去德尼罗 #
# Right next to De Niro #
# 但是我会永远带着头巾 #
# But I'll be hood forever #
- # 我是新一代的辛纳屈 # - 耶!
- # I'm the new Sinatra # - Yeah!
# 既然我可以在这里创造它 #
# And since I made it here #
# 我就能让它遍布世界各地 #
# I can make it anywhere #
# 他们对我的爱无处不在 #
# Yeah, they love me everywhere #
- # 在纽约  -  是的，嘿 #
- # In New York  - Yes, hey #
# 这个由梦筑城的钢筋混凝土的城市里 #
# Concrete jungle where dreams are made of #
# 你可以为所欲为  OK #
# There's nothin' you can't do, okay #
# 因为你现在在纽约... #
# Now you're in New York... #
啊，小孩
Ah, kids.
谁都喜欢小孩，是吧
Everybody loves them, right?
可能你也喜欢
You probably love kids.
- 嘿！ - 但我得承认
- Hey! - I got to admit...
我不喜欢
...I don't.
这就是我，我叫麦克
That's me, by the way. I'm Max.
就是你面前的小狗
I'm the little dog right there,
还好没有一堆熊孩子围在我身边
grateful I'm not being piled on by a horde of children.
等等我!
Wait for me!
我真是受不了这些孩子
Ugh. Can you believe that?
有个小孩不是挺好的吗
Having a kid looks like fun.
错了哥们，一点都不好
Nah, man, it ain't fun.
我跟你说人类家里有了小孩子
I'm telling you, once the humans bring a kid home,
生活就全变啦
your life ain't the same.
这种事儿我见得多了
Seen it a billion times.
找罪受
It changes you.
# 我来自帝国，那是... #
# I'm from the Empire State, that's... #
当然了，我以为
Now, I thought I never
我也不用担心这些事儿，可后来有一天...
had to worry about any of that, but then one day...
哦!
Ow!
- ...我主人凯蒂遇到了查克 - 嘿
- ...my owner Katie met Chuck. - Hey.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
哦，啊，没事
Oh. Uh, yeah.
- 没过多久，他们就结婚了 -你们好
- A little while later, they're married. - Hi, guys.
感觉不错
Which... it-it's great.
查克真的是个好人
Chuck is really... he's a good guy.
可是后来...
But then...
- 哦 - ...意外发生了
- Aw. - ...something happened.
凯蒂和查克有了个孩子
Katie and Chuck had a kid of their own.
名字叫利安
His name's Liam.
一开始，利安从早睡到晚
At first, he slept all the time.
每天就做做梦
Dreaming about, you know,
也不知道梦到什么东西了
whatever it is that babies dream about.
真可爱啊
Who's a cute little baby?
他睡他的觉...
He had his place...
你这个小可爱
You little cutie pie.
...我过我的日子
...and I had mine.
我以为一切会顺顺利利
Things seemed like they were gonna be fine.
啊呀呀呀
Wha...?
直到他开始说话了
Until he started talking.
再往后，他开始爬来爬去
And eventually, he started crawling.
突然间，这个家不单是我的窝了
Sort of.
And suddenly, my own home wasn't safe anymore.
因为被一个小恶魔霸占了
Th-There was a tiny monster taking it over.
现在，我能尽量离他远一点
Now, I did my best to keep a safe distance.
但是有一天
But then, one day,
利安做了件我怎么都想不到的事儿
Liam did something I never expected.
麦克
Max.
我好爱你
I love you, Max.
从那一刻起...
And from then on...
...一切都变了
...everything was different.
啊...
Ah...
我和杜老大，成了利安模仿的对象
Duke and I, we became like role models to him.
我该怎么说呢 他超喜欢我们
Like, what can I say? The-the kid's a fan.
# My love blossomed tenderly #
# My life grew sweeter through the years #
# I know that my baby loves me... #
他什么都想跟我们学
We try to be a good influence.
哇!
Whoa!
我们得好好教他
And we help him out whenever we can.
# Our love just won't end... #
这孩子真懂我们
This kid gets us.
泡泡!
Bubbles!
我们玩的很好
Yeah, we have fun.
泡泡!
Bubbles!
我还是不怎么喜欢小孩
And by the way, I'm still not a kid person.
我只是喜欢这个小孩
I'm talking about this kid.
这是我的小孩
This is my kid.
他最棒
He's perfect.
我绝对不会让我们家利安出任何事
And I'm never gonna let anything bad happen to him.
不过我得说，要保护他真是一刻都不能放松
But I got to say, keeping Liam safe is a full-time job.
啊
Ah.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
嗯...
Uh...
什么…  哦
Wha...? Ooh.
啊
Aah!
好了
All right.
嘿你好
Uh, hey. Uh, hello.
什么事都没有
Everything's cool.
我们没想找麻烦
Uh, we don't... we don't want any trouble.
利安
Liam?
没事吧哥们
You okay there, buddy?
这个世界一直都这么危险吗
Was the world always this dangerous?
乖狗狗
Good doggy.
不不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no!
不
No.
早上好 小白
Morning, Snowball.
谁是最最可爱的小白兔呀
Who's the best bunny in the whole wide world?
接招吧，大坏蛋
Take that, evildoer.
去找太阳玩吧
Off into the sun with you.
耶
Yeah!
耳朵
Ears up.
呼叫动物超级英雄
I'm calling this meeting
of the Superhero Animal Friends to order.
小马指挥官 请留意一下
Commander Horsey, please read the minutes
上次开会的发言
from our last meeting.
谢谢你
Thank you.
大家不要忘记为了打击坏蛋
Now, remember, everyone, crime is out there.
我们要时刻准备
We have to be ready.
来吧茉莉，该上学了
Come on, Molly, time to go.
哦，我上学要迟到了
Ooh, I'm gonna be late for school.
小白队长，你来代表我发言吧
Captain Snowball, you're in charge while I'm gone.
都听好啦，首先欢迎从洗衣机里回来的
First of all, I want to welcome White Thunder back
霹雳白熊
from the washing machine,
他跟一起洗的红色毛毯颜色染了
who was put in there with a red blanket
所以现在改叫...
and henceforth will be known as...
霹雳粉熊
Pink Thunder.
好了，我要出去巡逻了
Okay, I'm-a go check the perimeter.
亲爱的纽约早上好
Good morning, New York City!
小白
Snowball.
小白 你在干什么呢
Hey, Snowball, what are you doing?
你看不出来吗
What's it look like I'm doing?
准备打击坏蛋，小狗狗
I'm looking for crime, Tiny Dog.
我可是超级英雄啊
I'm doing superhero stuff.
噗 噗 噗 噗 噗
Thwip, thwip, thwip, thwip, thwip.
兄弟
Let me tell you something.
要是有人来这一片找事儿
Anybody comes in here looking for trouble,
我绝对要他好看
oh, they gonna meet my partners.
这就叫爪子里抠正义
I'm talking about Paw and Order.
呵呵，我说
Uh-huh. Okay, well, you do know
你是不是在模仿你的主人在扮演超级英雄啊
that your owner is just playing superhero, right?
你这是穿了超级英雄主题的睡衣
You're just wearing some superhero pajamas.
哈哈小狗狗你太天真了
Ha! Tiny Dog, you so naive.
只要你告诉我哪里有我需要救助的动物
Point me in the direction of any animal
然后就看我的
who needs my help, and stand back.
必杀技 看我的
Death blow!
行了行了 别嘚瑟了
Okay, okay, uh, I got it.
你那个小姑娘已经上学去了吗
So, uh, did your kid leave for school yet?
对对，她今天有个小测验
Yeah, yeah, no, she's got a quiz today.
测汉语拼音，她肯定没问题
Advanced spelling. She'll ace it, though.
听说测验答题不能涂改
You know, she writes her answers down in ink.
你说这什么学校啊
That's how confident she is.
听你这么说她挺聪明的
That sounds really smart.
不过我们家利安也很聪明
But you know what? Liam is smart, too.
有一天我听凯蒂说
In fact, I heard Katie say
我们家利安的头可比一般小孩大了不少
that Liam's head circumference is in the 80th percentile.
那就是大头娃娃了
Oh, that's cool. That's a lot of head.
我就想，他还随地尿尿吗
Hey, quick question: Is he still peeing everywhere?
还管不住自己吗
Can't control his bladder?
是啊，他还是随地尿
Yeah, he-he's... he's peeing.
不过我们宠物都知道撒尿能标记地盘
But-but every pet knows, if you pee on it, you own it.
可是利安没这概念
And Liam, he's just thinking ahead.
我看趁他没上幼儿园
Yeah, well, you still better
赶快教教他
train him before preschool starts.
你可并不希望以后有人
You don't want Liam to get a reputation
叫他尿尿大王吧
as one of those pee-pee kids.
是啊那是肯定的
Yeah, totally, like...
等等，幼儿园
Wait, preschool?
对啊，他快到年龄了
Yeah. He's around that age.
小鸟就要离开家了，小狗狗
The baby bird is leaving the nest, TD.
不不，小鸟就要老实待着
No, no. Baby bird is staying put.
他不用上幼儿园
He doesn't need preschool.
他可以待在家里...
He'll, you know...
家里有我在安全
stay home with-with me, where it's safe.
嘿 麦克
Hey, Max.
其实没什么大事，我说了你别激动
It's, uh, no big deal... no need to overreact...
就是，利安出门了
but, uh, Liam just left.
- 等等，他去哪了 - 不知道
- Wait, what? Where'd he go? - I don't know.
人去哪从不跟狗说
They never tell the dog specifics.
好吧 好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
大本营呼叫所有单位
This is Homebase to all units.
目标已经离开大楼了
The package has left the building.
有人看见利安了吗
Does anyone have eyes on him?
我没看见他，完毕
I don't see him. Over.
目标不在薯片袋子里，完毕
Well, he's not in this bag of chips. Over.
收到，等一下
Okay. Keep... Wait a minute.
你怎么觉得他会在薯片袋子里
Why would he be in a bag of chips?
大本营，我是鹰眼
Homebase, this is Eagle Eye.
你不要担心
Don't you worry.
目标一离开大楼
I had eyes on the package
我就看到他了，完毕
as soon as he left the building. Over.
目标平安无事
Subject is safe and sound,
现在正吃着一块像驼鹿的饼干
enjoying what looks to be a cookie shaped like a moose.
快吃吧
Here you go. Num-num.
搞错了
No, wait.
应该是驯鹿
It's a reindeer.
好吧，谢谢了馒头
Okay. Thanks, Norman.
你又乱抓乱挠了
Scratching again there, buddy.
真是... 他们连出门都不带我
I just... I really don't like it
真是太过分了
when they take him out without me.
杜老大
Hey, Duke.
哦
Ooh.
这是什么
What's this?
我知道，是个球
Oh, I know this! It's a ball.
去捡回来
Go get it.
麦克
Hey, Maxie.
不如我们出去走走
What say we go for a walk?
好吧我得承认，出来感觉不错
You know, I got to say, this is nice.
- 让我好好伸个...  -不!
- Good to stretch the... legs. - No!
- 我不要去看兽医!
- I don't want to go to the vet! - Hmm. Uh...
看兽医?不不不不不不
The vet? No! No, no, no, no, no!
哦，真倒霉，你居然骗我
Oh, not cool. You tricked me.
麦克，你别这样
Maxie, come on, boy.
你最近一直很焦虑的样子，放心，兽医会帮你的
You've been so stressed lately, but this vet is gonna help you.
走吧乖乖
Let's go, buddy.
好了
All right.
- 第一次来吗? - 哦，对
- First time here? - Uh, yeah.
佛朗西斯可是最好的兽医，没有之一哦
Oh, Dr. Francis is the best veterinarian in the business.
你会喜欢他的
You're gonna love him.
而且他最擅长治疗行为障碍
He specializes in behavioral disorders.
- 你是说行为障碍? - 是啊
- B-Behavioral disorders? - Yeah.
可我根本没有什么行为障碍
But I don't have a behavioral disorder.
我承认... 我是有点爱操心,
I-I-I mean... I-I mean, I worry a little, sure,
可是这个世界多危险啊
but it-it's a... it's a dangerous world.
不操心，那不是不正常吗
You-you'd be crazy not to... to worry.
我也很正常呵呵
Yeah, I'm fine, too.
我看铲屎官才是有病
It's my human that's nuts.
我也没干什么就给了她一只死鸟她就给扔了
I mean, you know, I-I bring her a dead bird, she throws it out.
还有一只死老鼠
I bring her a dead mouse,
她给扔垃圾桶啦
right in the garbage!
你说，我到底哪做的不好了，老妈?!
Is nothing I do good enough for you, Mother?!
天哪
Okay.
我跑跑跑跑跑啊
I run, and I run, and I run, and I run,
可我跑出去却发现，我无处可去
and I get out, and I've gone nowhere.
无处可去
Nowhere!
啊...
Uh...
我的主人总说, "你真是只好狗狗,"
My owner always says, "You're such a good dog,"
我呢，我也觉得我是只好狗
and I feel like a good dog,
可其实我要是只坏狗呢
but what if, deep down, I'm a bad dog?
万一我就是只坏狗呢?!
What if I'm a bad dog?!
我们点着火了
We start fires.
麦克
Max?
进来
Come on.
你听着麦克
I know, buddy.
只要你别再乱抓乱挠的
It's just until we can get
我就给你取下来，好吗?
this scratching thing under control, okay?
小蜜蜂!
Busy Bee!
麦克麦克
Max! Max!
麦克 你肯定想不到
Max. Max. You're never gonna believe it.
你这罩子还不错
Oh, hey, I like your cone.
我听见查克跟利安说我们要出去旅行了
Listen, I heard Chuck tell Liam that we're going on a trip.
真的吗? 那我们要坐车了?
Really? We're going in the car?
我们要坐车了!
We're going in the car!
车车车车车
Car, car, car, car, car, car!
生活处处有惊喜啊
Man, you know, life is funny.
上一秒你还要带防护罩
One minute, you're getting fitted for a cone,
下一秒你就能坐车了!
and the next, you get to go in a car!
你说的是你自己的情况，不过也对
Oh, I feel like that's very specific to you, but totally.
真是太棒啦
- Yeah. - This is incredible!
我等一下就回来
I'll be right back.
冰冰?
Chloe?
冰冰，我就要去旅行了
Chloe, I'm going on a trip, and I... Oh.
你能不能帮我...
I was wondering if you'd...
照看小蜜蜂...?
Will you watch my Busy Bee while I'm gone...?
是你呀，你刚才说话了?
Oh, hey, Max. Were you saying something?
对，我是想问你能不能...
Yeah. I was wondering if you could...
天哪
Oh... Okay.
真倒霉了
Never mind.
你头上带了个什么破玩意儿啊?
What's that stupid thing on your head?
啾啾?
Gidget?
啾啾，你在家吗?
Gidget, are you home?
啾啾?
Gidget?
你好麦克
Mm. Oh, hi, Max.
一起玩吗?
Do you want to join me?
我想跟你一起玩，啾啾,不过我告诉你
Oh, you know what, I really wish I could,
我就要去旅行了
but get this... I'm going on a trip.
哇哦，真的?
Wow. Really?
是啊，这可是大事
Yeah, it's a big deal.
我想求你，我走后帮我照看一下
I was wondering, could you watch my Busy Bee
小蜜蜂?
while I'm gone?
真是太可爱了
He is so cute.
可不是吗，小蜜蜂是我最喜欢的玩具
I know. It's my favorite toy in the whole world.
还有这张小脸
And that little face.
小脸多可爱
His little face.
哦对了对了，看好了
Oh, and-and ready?
哦，我喜欢
Oh, wow. I love him.
我第一眼就喜欢上她了
Oh, I just... I just love him immediately.
就好像我们是她爸妈
It's-it's like we're his parents.
你是爸爸我是妈妈
It's like you're the dad and I'm the mom
我们相爱有了这个孩子
and we're in a relationship and this is our baby.
这个...
Well...
难道不是吗，对不对
It's exactly like that. Exactly.
这个嘛... 好吧没错
It's not... Okay, yes.
你说是就是吧
Yes, that's exactly what it is.
所以你答应帮我照看小蜜蜂了?
Uh, so you'll watch Busy Bee while I'm gone?
麦克你去吧，到了那里好好玩
Max, you go, have a great time,
至于小蜜蜂，就交给我吧
and I want you to know I have got this.
谢谢了啾啾，回来见吧
Thanks, Gidget. See you later.
我就是拼了命也会保护好小蜜蜂的
I will defend Busy Bee with my life.
# Well, I'm on my way #
# I don't know where I'm going #
# I'm on my way... #
-拜托 老杜 别闹  - 嘿
- Come on, Duke! Go! - Okay.
太好了太好了，利安你感觉怎么样?
Yes, yes, yes. How we doing, Liam?
- 呜呼! - "呜呼" 就对了
- Whoo-hoo! - "Whoo-hoo" is right.
# Seein' me and Julio down by the schoolyard #
好吧
Okay.
# Seein' me and Julio down by the schoolyard... #
- 我们走咯!
- Yes! - Here we go!
-哦 哇  -喔 喔
- Oh, wow! - Whoo-hoo!
嘿朋友
Hey, man.
- 我坐车了! - 我们一样!
- I'm in a car! - Us, too!
我喜欢坐车!
I love the car!
- 坐车最棒了! - 是的!
- It's the best! - Yes!
# Well, I'm on my way #
# I don't know where I'm going #
# I'm on my way #
# And I'm taking my time, but I don't know where #
- Whee! - # So good-bye to Rosie #
# The queen of Corona #
# Seein' me and Julio down by the schoolyard #
行了大家下车
- Okay, come on, guys. - All right.
动作快点.
- Let's be quick. - Here we go.
# Seein' me and Julio down by the schoolyard. #
别别别.
No. No, no, no.
这边宝贝，来吧
- This way, buddy. Come on. - No!
嗯…
Mm...
哦不，糟了
Oh, no! Oh, no!
不不不不不!
Oh, no, no, no, no!
不不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
不...!
No...!
天啊，我都做了些什么?
Gidget, what have you done?
嗯？
Huh?
我们从今以后一刀两断
La Pasión de la Pasión.
为什么? 为什么?!
Why? Why?!
好的
Okay.
嗯？
Hmm?
怎么办，小蜜蜂
Oh, dear, sweet Busy Bee.
我要成为有八块臀肌的兔子
You know, I'm-a be the first bunny with washboard glutes.
不过臀肌是什么东西啊, 管他呢...
I'm not even sure what glutes are, but...
我可是肌肉兔
mine are gonna be shredded.
哦对对
Oh, yeah, yeah.
那还...挺厉害的
That's, uh... that's fascinating.
我跟你说
Let me tell you something.
只要会了它
Criminals are gonna take
我就有八块臀肌...
one good look at my glutes...
一门独享
and they just gonna give up.
这玩意肯定粘地板上了
Okay, this is obviously glued to the floor.
打扰一下，兔子，猫咪
Excuse me, rabbit, cat.
你们两个认不认识小白队长啊?
Do any of you know Captain Snowball?
小，小白队长.
Yeah, uh, ye-yes.
- 我们认识他. - 他又搞这套
- Yes, we do. - And here we go.
太好了.
Oh, good.
我的名字叫黛西，我有很重要的事情要找他
My name is Daisy, and I really got to talk to him.
有一只可怜的小动物现在需要救助
A poor, defenseless animal needs saving.
啊那你是想...?
Wha...? Are you saying...?
是的，我想请小白队长执行...
Yes. I need Captain Snowball for a...
一次绝密救援行动
top secret rescue.
懂了，我该走了
All right, well, I got to go.
很高兴认识你 你叫什么来着?
But nice meeting you, uh... What was it again?
好吧，你就没听
Okay, you don't listen.
- 我叫黛西 - 无所谓，我要...
- It's Daisy. - Whatever. Okay, I...
我要喊那个家伙拿点装备去帮忙
I got to get the dude to get the stuff to do the things.
拜拜
I got to... Bye-bye.
古里古怪
Mm-hmm. That was weird.
接下来会更古怪
Oh, sister, it's gonna get way weirder.
作战开始啦
It's Snow time, baby.
救命!
Help!
你们饿不饿?
Anybody hungry?
哈
Ha!
哦，小白队长
Oh, Snowball.
嗯，他没事吧?
Uh, is he okay?
你就放心吧，没事
Not in any way. No.
你们好.朋友们
Hello, citizens.
这是啥呀?
Who is that? Mm-mm-mm.
我就是小白队长
I'm Captain Snowball.
听说有人需要我帮忙
I hear one of you needs my help.
哦，是我
Ooh, that's me.
太好啦
Ah, very good.
新来的，说说有什么事
New dog, tell me your story.
好的，是这样
Okay. Well, it all began
事情发生时我正在度假回来的路上
when I was on my way back from vacation.
人类都好好待在
Our humans were safely stowed
飞机上面的隔间里
in the overhead compartment,
而我们则在检查他们的行李
and we were going through our owners' stuff.
人一丢行李就怪航空公司
Humans always blame the airline.
你要换什么?
What do you got?
我要用两双袜子换你一条运动短裤
I'll trade you two socks for a pair of workout shorts.
袜子干不干净?
Are they clean or dirty?
我看不干净
They ain't clean.
没错，快臭死啦
Nope. They nasty.
那时候我听到一个声音
And then I heard a noise.
我不懂野生动物的语言...
Now, I don't speak wild animal...
...不过据我所知,
...but from what I gathered,
他叫小虎, 是一只怕生又可爱的小老虎
he was a scared, adorable tiger cub named Hu.
那只可怜的小老虎被人锁在了笼子里
This poor baby kitty was being held against his will.
哇
Whoa.
- 这种事谁能信啊 -说的是啊?
- That is unbelievable. - I know, right?
不，我的意思是我不信，你别瞎掺和
No, I mean I literally don't believe a word of it.
别见怪
No offense. Or do take offense.
你见怪都行反正无所谓
I'm good either way.
不好意思，我还真的是非常见怪
Um, pardon me. Offense is very much taken.
我说的是真的，现在情况更糟了
That story happened, and it gets worse.
飞机落地之后，我又看到了小虎
After the plane landed, I saw Hu again.
给我用力推!
Use your no-good clown muscles and push!
他被送到了新主人那里
He was being brought to his new owner.
- 可那个时候... - 时间就是钞票!
- And this guy... - Time is rubles!
那个人就是一个,
Y'all, this guy was pure,
彻头彻尾的马戏团恶魔
concentrated circus evil.
小老虎需要小白队长拯救
That tiger needs Captain Snowball.
- 黛西我们走 - 好的!
- Daisy, let's go. - Yeah!
拯救小老虎
Let's free that tiger.
- 死也不放弃 - 这个，我说...
- Or die trying. - Well, I mean...
只是有可能
- I mean, we might. - Um...
八成是你死
- Probably you. - Huh?
你穿炫酷超人装，谁都会注意你的
You're wearing a bright suit. Everyone's gonna notice you.
我就没事了
I'll be fine.
醒醒，我们到了
Hey, guys, we're here.
太好了
Yay.
你们好
Hey there.
谢普叔叔，你好
There's Uncle Shep.
欢迎来到农场
Welcome to the farm.
小宝贝在哪呢
Where's my little man?
哇
Oh, wow!
真是个好地方啊
Look at this place.
是啊  这...
Yeah, it's...
有这么多
Oh, so many smells
我闻都没闻过的味道
I have never smelled before.
我的鼻子要忙不过来了
My nose is so confused.
太幸福了!
And happy!
来吧麦克，咱们探险去吧
Come on, Max. Let's go explore.
噢
Oh!
等等我
- Yeah! - Uh, wait up.
喔
Oh!
嘿，奶牛，哞
Hey, cow. Moo.
你是奶牛，应该冲我哞
You're a cow. You're supposed to moo.
汪汪
Woof, woof.
什么?
What?
哦我是狗狗
Oh, I'm a dog.
我像个大傻瓜一样摇尾巴
I'm wagging my tail like an idiot.
哦好吧大姐你真逗
Oh, okay. Dude, not cool.
哦，你们扔球玩吗? 求你们扔个球
Oh, are you gonna throw a ball? Oh, please throw a ball.
让我追着玩吧，因为我的大脑
And I will chase it because my brain
比老鼠粑粑还小
is the size of a rat turd.
好吧，我明白了
Okay. Yeah, I get it.
你学的可真像
You made your point.
快看呐我往树上尿尿
- Yeah, yeah. - Oh, look. I'm peeing on a tree.
- 这棵树是我的了 - 行了行了
- I now own this tree. - Okay. Yeah, great.
- 我们这就走 - 我就盯着这扇门
- Leaving now. All right. - I guess I'll just stare
看你什么时候回来
at the door until you come back!
我想念纽约了
Oh, I miss New York.
离开城市一阵子可能会对比较好
Maybe a break from the city is just what you need.
这个地方...
This place is...
怎么...?
Wha...?
不不不不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
老杜，我干什么了，我干什么了
Duke, what did I do? What did I do?
哇哦
Whoa.
晚饭好了!
Dinner's on!
冰冰? 你得帮帮我
Chloe? I need your help.
冰冰
Chloe.
噢  呃  噢
Oh. Uh... oh.
冰冰?
Uh, Chloe?
- 你这是在干嘛? - 嘘
- Chloe, are you okay? - Shh.
抱歉 我是想找你...
Sorry. Uh, I'm-I'm just... I'm...
怎么回事，你头上为啥带个灯罩啊?
Real quick... why is there a lampshade on your head?
听着啾啾亲爱的
Listen, Gidget, baby,
我要跟你说实话
I got to be honest with you.
我主人给了我一点点一丢丢猫薄荷
My owner might have given me a little bit of catnip.
好吧，我懂了
Oh, okay. Gotcha.
挺好的
That's great. Um, listen.
是特别好，啾啾
It is great, Gidget.
我觉得好极了...
Everything is great...
好极了
All right.
- 听到了吗? - 听到什么?
- Do you hear that? - Hear what?
像是有一台小小的发动机
It's like... it's like a tiny... like a tiny motor.
发出了嗡嗡声
It's like a humming sound.
你到底想说什么
I'm not... don't know what you're ta...
你在打呼噜
Oh. Chloe, you're purring.
是你自己
That's you.
什么? 是我吗?
What? That's me?
你说这个声音是我发出来的?
Like, as in the sound is coming from inside of me?
是啊
- Yep. - Oh.
不知道我还能发出什么样的声音
I wonder what other sounds I could make.
你听我说
It-it's just, Max trusted me
麦克让我照顾他的小蜜蜂，但是我...
to look after his Busy Bee, and then...
你听我说好吗?
Chloe, would you listen?
别闹了
Wow. Please stop.
你有完没完?
Are you finished?
这事很重要
This is important.
我弄丢了小蜜蜂
I lost Busy Bee.
我得把他找回来，但是要想找回来...
I got to get it back, but to do that...
冰冰...
Chloe...
你得好好教教我
I need you to teach me
怎么扮成猫
the way of the cat.
看我的，我要抓住你
Here we go. I'm gonna get you.
麦克快来呀，跟我抓萤火虫
Max, come on. Try to catch a firefly.
听起来是很好玩
I'm just... That sounds great,
但是我觉得利安需要我陪着
but I-I think Liam wants me near him.
这地方挺古怪的
You-you know, he's a little freaked out
他有点吓坏了
being in this weird place.
他什么事都不会有
I think he'll be okay.
这是个大虫子
And this one is a jumper.
好吧
O-Okay.
就一只
Just one.
太好了
Yes, I...
哦，你好
Oh. Hello.
狗这辈子有两样宝贵的:
Dog's got two things in this life:
一个是水盆，一个是尊严
his water bowl and his dignity.
你动了我的水盆就是伤了我的尊严
You take one, you take the other.
我，我不知道这是你的水盆
I, uh... I-I didn't know this was your bowl.
你眼睛被罩子挡住了是吗?
What? The cone blocking your view?
上边写着我的名字呢
It's got my name on the side.
我们非常抱歉，你是叫，小鸡
We are so sorry, Mr. Chicken.
我可不叫小鸡
Name's not Chicken.
你们看我长得像小鸡吗?
Do I look like a chicken to you?
不像，一点都不像
- No. No, sir. - No, not-not even a little.
他们叫我鲁叔
- Name's Rooster. - Oh.
哦，鲁叔，我叫麦克，这是...
Okay. I-I'm Max, and this is...
他们把小娃娃关在笼子里干什么?
Hey, what's that kid doing in the cage?
她怎么了? 难道发烧了?
There something wrong with him? He got the fever?
他是，他叫利安
Uh, that's-that's Liam.
他喜欢乱跑
He-he likes to run.
那就让他跑啊
So let him run.
这个嘛，他跑的特别快
Well, Liam's super fast.
我们眨个眼，他就能上树
We-we-we blink, and he's up a tree.
小孩爬树上有什么问题吗?
So then your kid's up a tree. What's the problem?
他会摔下来的
Well, he could fall.
- 真没准 -然后他就会受伤
- He might. - And then he hurts himself.
那他肯定是在你想象的那棵树上爬的太高了?
Oh, so he got really high up in this hypothetical tree?
这个
Kid gets hurt,
小孩要受了伤才能记住教训
he learns not to do it again.
你知道我啃了多少根电线吗?
You know how many electric cords I've chewed?
我猜，你啃了很多根?
Like, multiple cords?
一根
One.
差点电死我
It shocked me.
我倒着走了俩礼拜的路
I walked backwards for a week,
后来就长记性了
but I never chewed a cord again.
这样对你挺好的
Well, that is great for you.
难怪你成了这个样子
And-and it explains a lot,
不过我不想让利安受到任何伤害
but I like to protect Liam from... everything.
好吧，那是你，可你错了
Well, that's you, and you're wrong.
他也有点太那个了
Can you believe that guy?
是啊，他太酷了!
Yeah, he was cool!
不，他一点都不酷
No, he wasn't.
说得对，他一点都不酷
I know. He wasn't cool at all.
我来洗碗吧
No, I'll do the dishes.
走吧.
Come on.
回家 我们进屋吧
Let's get this guy inside.
谢谢
Thanks.
站着被动，狗狗只能睡外面
Whoa. Hold up there. Dogs sleep outside.
什么
- Uh, pardon? - Huh?
你别走啊
Whoa. Whoa, whoa, whoa. Okay, wait, wait.
咱们先谈谈...
L-L-Let's talk about this like rational...
好啦，我们到了
All right, we're here.
速度打破纪录，多亏了我的兔子车
In record time, too, thanks to the Bunnymobile.
棒呆了!
Oh, yeah!
隐身模式
Stealth mode.
我们走!
Let's go!
别大惊小怪的
You are jumpy.
怎么了
I meant... That's cool.
我这是
Or...
看见没那有个东西我一点都不怕
Look at that thing I'm not scared of right there.
这马路上有块糖纸
Or... There's a candy wrapper on the ground.
瞧，我没事就爱叫两声
See? It's just a thing I do.
快上啊，你这只傻老虎!
Come on, you stupid tiger!
他在那里面
There he is.
快走
Let's go.
我可不想跟你耗一整夜
We don't have entire night.
给我跳啊!
Let's go!
你浪费我宝贵的时间
You're wasting Sergei's time.
我们不能就这样看着
We got to do something.
-好的  好的  -哇 哇
- Okay, all right, all right. - Whoa, whoa.
等等
Wait.
咱们走
Come on.
明天我们继续训练
We try again tomorrow.
玩不了杂耍的老虎...
If tiger does not do trick...
只能剥了皮做毯子
tiger will become rug.
你们都给我盯紧这只傻老虎
Do not let tiger out of your sight.
没事了，小虎
It's okay, Hu.
是我，黛西，飞机上那个
It's me, Daisy, from the plane.
嘿，你们最好离老虎远一点
Hey. Step away from the tiger.
别管我的闲事，蠢狼
Mind your business, wolf.
噢
Oh!
哈哈
Ha-ha!
哇哦
Whoa!
糟糕
No!
要死了要死了!
Oh, gonna die, gonna die, gonna die!
我拿到钥匙了，快走
I got the keys. Let's go.
什么?
What?
我是说, "我拿到钥匙了"
I said, "I got the keys."
赶快走
Come on, let's go.
没问题，对，该走了
Uh, all right. Yeah, of course.
太好了!
Heck yeah!
你猜我学到了什么?
You know what I learned today?
狼都是坏家伙
- Hmm? - Wolves are jerks.
杜老大
Duke.
Psst. Duke.
咱们俩得去看看利安
I think we should check on Liam.
-老杜. - 总算抓住尾巴了
- Duke. - I finally caught you, tail.
什么声?
Huh? What's that?
没事，没事
Okay. Okay.
什么?
What?
等等 等等
Wait, wait. Wait, wait, wait, wait.
别过来, 求求你不要吃我
No, no, please, you don't want to eat me.
我瘦得皮包骨头，不不不不不...
I'm skin and bones. No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no...
谢谢
Uh... Thanks.
刚才是我一时没注意
He, uh... he got the jump on me.
主要是...
I guess he...
罩子挡着了我没看到他
I couldn't see him because of the cone.
- 那就把罩子拿掉啊 - 我也想拿掉
- Then get rid of the cone. - Oh, man, I would.
我也想，但是医生非让我带着
I would, but my therapist says I need it.
哦这样啊
Oh. Oh, okay.
好吧，那也难怪了
Well, that makes sense.
这是医疗器械嘛
Yeah, it's a medical device.
那些医生
These doctors.
行了
There.
你病好了
You're cured.
玩去吧
Hallelujah.
太过分了
Not a fan.
我越来越不喜欢这个农场了
I am not a fan of the farm.
尾巴，可以了
Okay, tail.
耳朵
Ears.
- 现在都齐了 - 哇
- And voilà. - Whoa.
啾啾，你现在看可真像猫咪，太神奇了
Gidget, you look so much like a cat, it's crazy.
是啊，谁想得到?
Yeah. Who knew?
- 很简单. - Whoa, whoa, whoa.
- So easy. - Whoa, whoa, whoa.
光有假耳朵
Hold on. It's gonna take more
和袜子尾巴可不够，懂吗?
than fake ears and a sock, okay?
你得好好学学怎么当一只猫咪
You got to learn how to act like a cat.
好的 我现在
- Okay. - Okay, Gidge, I'm gonna throw
给你设定几个场景，而你只需要...
some situations at you, and you're just gonna, you know...
- 表现的像猫咪 - 明白
- you're gonna react like a cat. - Gotcha.
捡回来
Fetch.
好的!
- Yes! - I'm gonna get it!
啾啾，停下
Gidget, stay.
- 但是... - 记住
- But... - No.
猫咪才不会捡东西呢，只有傻瓜才去捡
Cats don't care about fetching. Fetching is for dopes.
那样有失身份，因为你是只猫咪
You're above that, because you are a cat.
嗯
Mm.
你瞧。狗狗落地时候
You see, dogs land
会摔成狗啃泥
like the clumsy oafs they are.
而我们猫咪是用爪子落地
Meanwhile, cats land on their feet.
- 真的吗? - 要怎么...
- Really? - How do they...
太好了!
Yes! I did it!
我做到用爪子落地了
I landed on my feet.
- 厉害! - 干得漂亮
- Yes! - Nice work.
我好像打坏什么东西了
Seriously, guys, I think I broke something.
必须的，猫咪也得方便
You gotta. It's a fact of life.
我才不要呢。你想都别想
Absolutely not. Never gonna happen.
我找到好吃的了!
Guys, I found treats!
嗯，大毛，恶心
Oh, Mel. Ugh.
好了，啾啾，吃了小绿豆
Okay, Gidget, eat Sweetpea.
什么?
What?
猫咪吃小鸟，这是天性
Cats eat birds. It's nature.
- 这个还是过了吧 -不不不
- Yeah, I'm gonna pass. - No, no, no, no.
猫砂那部分你已经跳过了
You used your one pass on the litter box,
这个你可不能省略
so you have to do this.
- 但... - 但但但什么但... 快去呀
- But... - B-B-B-But... Do it.
你真的让啾啾吃了小绿豆吗?
You're seriously gonna make her eat Sweetpea?
不不，当然不是啊。我就是吓...
Oh, no, no, no. Of course not. I'm just freaking her out.
我吃了，然后呢?
Okay. What's next?
吐，你真是...
Gidget, no. That's...
坏狗狗，坏猫狗
Bad dog. Bad cat-dog.
抱歉
Sorry.
上来
Up.
用尾巴蹭脸
And tail in the face.
很好，用屁股推杯子
Okay, touch the butt to the cup.
上键盘走猫步
Walk on keyboard.
就是这样
There you go.
咖啡泼电脑上
Coffee on computer.
现在下去
And down.
厉害
Nice.
对，有感觉了
Yes, you got it.
啾啾，你现在已经很像猫了
Gidget, you're as close to a cat as a dog can get.
有本事你把我变成一只毛丝鼠啊
Cool. Now turn me into a chinchilla.
你能做到吗
Can you do that?
好极了
Oh, yeah.
首次任务完成了
First mission in the bag.
轻而易举
It was easy.
太简单了吗
Too easy? Maybe.
可能吧，可能太简单了
Maybe it was.
# Come along and ride on a fantastic voyage... #
你好啊大兄弟
Hey, big fella.
我干嘛去了，救了只老虎玩而已
What'd I do? Oh, I just rescued a tiger.
我可不是在吹牛
No, I'm not even trying to brag.
这是事实
I'm just telling you what happened.
当牛人就这点不好
See, that's the thing about being awesome.
牛人说真话
When you awesome and you just tell the truth,
都让人觉得你肯定在吹牛
it sounds like you bragging.
等你吹完牛了跟我说一声
Let me know when you finish tooting your horn,
咱们还得给小虎找个安全的地方
'cause we got to find a safe place for Hu.
什么，你什么意思?
Uh, what? What are you talking about?
哦对
Oh, yeah.
他还在呢，对
Oh, that guy. Yeah.
对
Uh... yeah.
有办法了
Oh! I got it.
我有个朋友的主人从不回家
I know a guy whose owner is never home.
带小虎去他那
Yeah, we can just take him there.
听上去靠谱
Sounds like a plan.
启动超级兔子之力
Superbunny powers, activate.
你先在外边等着
Wait out here, buddy.
我马上回来，好吗?
We'll be right back, okay?
# I'm a puppy cute and sweet #
# Beg real nice and get a treat. #
Hip, hip, hip,
hip, hip, hip.
- 嘿老头 - 谁来啦?
- Hey, Pops. - Who-who's that?
兔子兔子兔子!
Bunny, bunny, bunny, bunny!
我可是英雄，你们放尊重一点
I am a hero. I need you to respect that.
别闹，别闹
All right, all right.
立正!
Ten-hut!
狗感学校现在开课
Puppy school is in session.
狗感学校?
Puppy school?
开始每日宣誓
Now the daily pledge.
-我宣誓... - 我宣誓...
- I promise... - I promise...
- ...要听老头的话.. - ...要听老头的话...
- ...to listen to Pops... - ...to listen to Pops...
...学着当一只有
...and learn how to be adorable,
无敌狗狗眼的小可爱...
wide-eyed and loving...
...学着当一只有
...and learn how to be adorable, wide-eyed
无敌狗狗眼的小可爱...
and loving...
...这样我想要什么就会有什么
...to get what I want, when I want it.
...这样我想要什么
...to get what I want,
就会有什么
when I want it.
现在注意，突击测验
Okay, now, Pop's quiz.
麦伦把袜子藏在了屋里的各个角落
Myron has hidden socks all over the room.
那我们要怎么处理这些袜子呢?
Now, what do we do with human socks?
我我
Ooh, me, me.
请回答，小公主
Go ahead, Princess.
藏起袜子，老头老师
We hide them, Mr. Pops.
回答正确
Correct-a-rooney.
为什么要藏袜子呢?
And why do we hide them?
因为找不到另一只袜子就会特别伤脑筋
Not knowing where one sock is messes with the humans' minds.
太对了，就得让人类猜不出来
Heck yes, it does. Always keep 'em guessing.
去把袜子找出来
Now, go find those socks.
什么？好吧 好吧
What? Okay, all right.
行了.
Okay. Hey, Pops.
行了行了，够了
What...? Okay, that's enough.
怎么回事?
Hey. What's going on?
主人又弄了一只小狗仔
Yeah. My owner got a new puppy.
我叫小不点
My name's Tiny.
谁管你叫什么!
Nobody cares!
我本来在教他怎么避免成为傻狗
I was teaching Tiny how not to be anyone's sucker.
谁知道消息走漏了，周边
Word got out, suddenly every puppy
三个州的小狗仔都来挠我的门
in the tristate area is scratching at my door.
哦
Yeah. Oh.
老头老师?
Professor Pops?
怎么了，酸瓜?
Yes, Pickles?
我好想拉臭臭
I got to make a poop.
这个我教过你们，随便找只鞋
Oh. You know where to do that. Find a shoe.
真是太可爱了.
This is so sweet.
是啊，就是可爱...
Yeah, they're good...
老天我的妈呀! 这是什么呀?
Holy cheese and crackers! What is that?
麦伦，警报!
Myron, horn!
别别别，你听我说，没事的
No, no, no. No, no, look, look. It's okay.
这个漂亮的动物叫小虎
This beautiful creature is Hu.
有个好消息...
And the good news...
他要跟你们一起住
is he's staying with you.
趁这老虎没把我家拆了，赶紧把他弄走
Get that tiger out of here before he does any more damage.
可是我们没地方给他住啊
But we don't have anywhere else to take him.
- 反正他不能住在这
- Well, he ain't staying here. - Kitty, kitty,
你们干什么... 别跟他交朋友
No, what are you... Don't get attached.
他要离开这里
That thing is out.
哦，小酸瓜
Oh, Pickles.
找到鞋拉臭臭了吗?
Did you poop in a shoe?
我拉到了一只靴子里
I pooped in a boot.
你主人肯定发现不了
Your owner won't find it for weeks.
你是在哭吗?
Are you crying?
你才哭了呢!
What? No. You're crying!
不过我真替酸瓜感到骄傲
But I'm just so proud of Pickles.
老头老师
Mr. Pops,
就让老虎留下来吧，好吗?
please, can the tiger stay with us?
求你了?
Please?
求你了
Please.
麦伦都怪你
Myron, look away.
真是要了命了
Oh, flap-doodle.
行了可以，就一个晚上
Okay, fine. One night.
真是拿你们没办法
I taught you guys too well.
我只要你们干一件事
I give wolves one job.
看好那只老虎
Guard white tiger.
一群蠢狼，都是笨蛋
And you wolves, you blow it.
也许我该让这只杂耍小猴
Maybe I should make juggling monkey
负责安保工作
head of security.
你说呢，小赛尔猴?
What say you, Little Sergei?
是的，你个小机灵鬼
Yes, you are so smart.
可至于那个家伙吗
And then there's this one.
没见过比你更蠢的狼
You're the worst wolf ever.
我发誓我...
I swear, I...
这是什么?
What this?
这是偷老虎的贼留下的
This from thief of tiger.
没错闻闻
Yes, smell.
把那只老虎给我找回来
You bring that tiger back.
办不到的话。你们的皮...
And if you don't, that one...
...就给小赛尔猴当衣服穿了
...will be a new coat for Little Sergei.
太好吃了
Oh, this is good.
你该尝尝这个
You should really try this. Mm!
-太棒了  -真新鲜
- So nice. - So fresh.
麦克
Max.
书书书
Book, book, book.
我要看这书
We're turning it again.
对不起利安 我们不认识字
Um, I'm sorry, Liam. We can't read.
别呀，很简单
Well, wait a sec. There's no reason
我们一起研究一下就行了，对吧
we can't figure this one out together, right?
这本书的第一页,
This first page,
一个小女孩戴着一顶小红帽
there's a little girl in a red hood,
她穿过森林还带着...
skipping through the forest with...
还带着食物
with some food.
快看呀... 她有食物
Look at that... she's got food.
再看这边...
And look at that...
小红帽把食物带给了...
she brought the food over to...
你说，这是谁啊?
Hmm. Say, who is that?
看起来像她外婆.
Oh! Looks like her grandma.
肯定是她外婆
Oh, I'll bet you're right.
真是贴心啊，她...
Oh, that is sweet. She...
外婆有了一只宠物狼
So, Grandma had a pet wolf.
小红帽玩的很好，然后就回家了
They had a great visit. The little girl went home.
没人被吃掉，讲完了
No one got eaten. The end.
不不不不
No, no, no, no.
这个故事你讲错了
That's not how the story goes.
这没你什么事
We got this, thanks.
那只狼接来下想吃了小
That wolf was gonna eat the little girl.
打住，谢谢你了，鲁叔
Nope! Thank you, Rooster.
他先把小女孩的外婆吃了
He already ate Grandma.
然后又假扮成那个小女孩的外婆
And then he assumed the old lady's identity.
不
No.
别吓着我们家利安
Wha...? Hey. Don't freak out my kid.
大坏蛋，大坏狼
Take that, Mr. Wolfy.
我看这小孩没事
Kid seems fine to me.
是你在害怕这害怕那
You're the one who's scared of everything.
我才没有，老杜，你跟他说
I am not. I'm-I'm... Tell him, Duke.
对对，麦克才没有害怕这害怕那
Yeah, yeah. Max isn't scared of everything.
我能举例子...
I-I... I can think of, um...
没错，对，有好几个...
Uh, yeah. Yeah, well, there's a few...
- 有好几个例子呢 - 行了，谢谢
- there's a few things. - Okay, thanks.
不客气
You bet.
好了，开始吧
Okay, this is it.
- 准备好了吗? - 没问题
- You good to go? - Roger that.
真是奶奶的乖猫猫
That's a good kitty.
玛利亚，你的脸上
Maria, your face,
充满了悲伤
it wears a thousand sorrows.
小蜜蜂
Busy Bee.
不是吧
Oh, boy.
没事，啾啾你行的
Okay, come on, Gidget.
啊
Huh?
馒头，快！
Norman, now!
别急看我的
You got it, sister.
小蜜蜂!
Busy Bee!
好吧，启动备用计划
Whoa. Okay. Uh, time for plan B.
启动备用计划
Engaging plan B.
她抓住了红点
She caught the red dot.
万岁!
Huzzah!
她就是天选之猫
She is the Chosen One.
女王陛下万岁
All hail the queen.
女王万岁!
Hail the queen!
啾啾女王万岁
All hail Queen Gidget.
快
Hyah!
快进去!
Get in! Faster!
麦克，你看见没有?
Max, did you see that?
- 当然. - 太酷啦
- Uh, yeah. - So cool.
这根本不算什么
Oh, it's not that big a deal.
进去，快!
Move. Hyah!
别磨蹭!
Move it!
哦，真帅
Oh, man.
你看那大家伙出来了
Hey, look. That big guy got out.
我们快去叫鲁叔
We better get Rooster.
不用，用不着叫他
No. No, no, no need for that.
我自己能搞定
I can handle it.
嘿先生
Hey, mister.
来吧，回到猪圈里
Ba-Back inside.
- 快点 - 加油
- Come on. - Yep.
再使点劲
You're doing great.
从下面推
Go underneath him.
给我回去
Let's go.
好像动了一点点
I think he moved a little.
你不准，不准当没看见我
Don't you... don't you ignore me.
啊，拜托
Ah, come on.
去他前面. 不，后面
Now go and do the front. No, no, back.
从侧面推
Now go to the side.
麦克，刚才奶牛不走，鲁叔就咬他们
Uh, Max, Rooster nips at the cows to get 'em to move.
真的吗? 那太过分了吧...
Really? That sounds drastic, but...
不过这是你自找的
okay, pig, you asked for this.
- 嘿，麦克你没事吧? - 没事
- Hey, Max. You okay? - Yeah.
出什么事了?
What's going on?
别担心我没事
Don't worry, I'm-I'm fine.
你把绵羊都放出去了
You let all the sheep out.
- 我有吗? - 嘿!
- I did? - Hey!
全都给我回去! 快点
Get back in there! Come on.
先等一下，小绵哪去了?
Wait a minute. Where's Cotton?
哦，小绵去树林了
Oh, he went into the woods.
- 你. - 哎...
- You. - Uh...
你跟我一起来
Come with me.
你让我跟你，去哪?
Wh-Where are we going?
跟我去把小绵找回来
We're gonna go get Cotton back.
哦，那好啊
Oh. Great.
走吧杜老大
- Come on, Duke. - Oh.
- 杜老大，坐下  - 是
- Duke, sit. - Yep.
这次只有你和我
This is just you and me.
哦，糟了
Oh, boy.
跟上
Come on.
没事
Super.
回头见!
Good-bye!
小绵，你在哪?
Cotton, where are you?
快点
Come on.
别磨蹭!
Hurry up!
好吧
Okay.
跳过来
Just jump.
嗷 喔 喔
Ow, ow, ow!
闻到小绵的味了
Scent's getting stronger.
他就在附近
Cotton's close.
不是吧
Oh, boy.
我上的去
I can do this.
我能行，我能行
I got it, I got it.
鲁叔，这样吧，你先去吧
Rooster, you-you know what? Just... just go on without me.
- 你别想给我撂挑子. -我有点...
- Oh, you're not giving up. - Yeah, but...
快跟我来
Follow me.
小绵，你跑下面干什么?
Cotton, what are you doing down there?
这棵树上有苹果
There's apples in this tree.
好的小绵，别害怕
All right, just don't panic.
我的天
Oh, man.
麦克这就下去把你救上来
Max is coming down to save you.
等等，什么
Wait, what?
那棵树太小，经不住我的体重
That tree can't support my weight.
得你下去
You get down there.
我肯定不行
I-I-I can't do that.
你当然行
Sure, you can.
你当然行，就当你是在玩...接球游戏
Think of this as a... as a... as a game of fetch.
现在快去把小绵救回来
Now, go fetch the sheep.
不不不不不
No. No, no, no, no, no.
这太高了, 而且我很...
It-it's too high, and-and I'm-I'm...
我很害怕
I'm too afraid.
麦克，我教你一招
Max, here's a trick.
要想不害怕，你第一件事就是
The first step of not being afraid
要装的一点都不害怕
is acting like you're not afraid.
怎么，你害怕吗?
So, are you scared?
不
No.
你害怕吗?
Are you scared?
不，我不害怕
No! No, I'm not.
这就对了
Now you're talking.
去救小绵
Go get Cotton.
快点
Hurry.
好吧
Okay, okay.
嘿
Hey.
拼了
Okay.
听着，小绵
Listen, uh, Cotton,
往我这走，好吗?
walk toward me, okay?
好的，行
Okay, sure.
可是我的腿卡住了
But my leg is stuck.
他的腿卡住了
His leg is stuck.
那你就帮他弄开
Well, unstuck it.
好
Uh...
抓紧
- Hold on. - Whee!
小绵，听着，我们...
Okay, Cotton, listen, we got to...
快点!
Hurry up!
加油
Come on.
好了
Okay.
我们...我们没死
We're... we're alive.
当然
Yep.
对, 我们...
Yeah, we... Oh, no!
我们没死
Oof. Yeah, we are.
麦克?
Max?
麦克
Max.
回羊圈里去，小绵
Get back in your pen, Cotton.
- 好的 - 走反了
- Okay. - No. Other way, Cotton.
好的
Okay.
情况怎么样? 出什么事了?
So, how did it go? What-what happened?
你知道吗，老杜，刚才特别惊险
You-you know, it was... it was pretty intense.
鲁叔，你跟他说
Tell him, Rooster.
没什么，就是出了点意外
You know, some stuff happened.
现在没事了
Now it's over.
哇哦
Wow!
鲁叔可真会讲故事
He can really tell a story.
那当然了
Right?
他就在附近
We are getting closer.
于是就这样，一群饿狼把我团团围住
So there I was, surrounded by nasty wolves.
你问我当时害不害怕?
You asking, was I scared?
我们什么也没问
No one asked anything.
你跑过来就开始跟我们说个不停
You just walked up to us and started talking.
我其实很害怕
I was scared.
但我还是救下了小老虎
But I saved that tiger anyway.
我是英雄吗?
Am I a hero?
这个不该由我决定
That's not for me to say.
波波
Boo-Boo.
- 波波你在听我说吗?
- Boo-Boo, are you listening? - I am.
别在那挖土了波波
Stop digging for a second, Boo-Boo,
听听没准能学到点东西
and maybe you'll learn something.
我刚刚说到...
As I was saying...
有有...有狼
Wo-Wo... W-W-Wolf.
对呀，我一直都在说狼好吗
Duh. That's what I've been talking about... wolves.
那边
There.
那只老虎在哪?
Where is the tiger?
哦，他在那!
Oh. There he is!
什么?
What?
嘿
Hey!
再见啦，傻瓜!
So long, suckers!
接招!
Ha! Take that!
这才叫训练
Now, this is training.
懂吗，越练反应越快
Okay? Keeping my reflexes sharp.
大获全胜
Ha! Flawless victory.
噢
Oh!
你被一只兔子打败了
You were just beaten by a rabbit.
可你都不知道
You don't even know it.
哦，披萨到了
Ooh, my pizza rolls.
什么声音?
What's that?
啊
Oh.
你好啊小白
Oh, hello, Snowball.
老头
Hey, Pops.
怎么了，出什么事了?
What's, uh... what's-what's going on?
没什么，我把你的老虎送回来
Oh, you know, just returning your giant tiger.
有件小事:
Oh, uh, fun fact:
他把我家给毁了!
He trashed my apartment!
而且他还偷吃我的电视机，跟吃饼干似的
This thing ate a flat-screen like it was a pita chip.
真不害臊!
For shame!
瞧瞧你干的好事
Oh, now you've done it.
酸瓜快气死了
Pickles is pissed.
你确定他是我的老虎?
Uh... are you sure that's my tiger?
其实我也不确定...
'Cause I don't... I don't know if that's...
我们走，同学们
Let's go, class.
拜托老头，你别这样啊
Ah, come on, old man, don't do this.
喂喂喂，别走
Wait, wait, wait, wait, wait, wait.
别走啊
Please.
嗨
Hey.
你还好吗?
How you been?
我现在要去拿我的披萨
I'm-a go get back to my pizza rolls,
待会再来看你，好吗?
and I'll come back and check on you in a bit, okay?
问题解决了
Problem solved.
小白?
Snowball?
毛毛狗?
Puffy Dog?
你跑到人家麦克家里干什么呢?
What are you doing in Max's apartment?
没什么，倒是你
Nothing. Why are you hanging out
为什么跟一群猫混在一起?
with every cat in the universe?
你懂的，不为什么
Oh, you know, just because.
嗯，那好吧
Mm, okay.
那好吧
Okay.
好吧
你好啊，鲁叔
Uh, hey, Rooster.
小家伙，今天表现不错
Hey, kid. Good job today.
是吗，说起来我必须承认我感觉很好
Yeah? Well, I-I got to admit, I feel pretty good.
我现在已经不怎么害怕农场，还有你，还有那只...
I'm not so nervous around the farm or you or...
那只一直跟着我的怪火鸡!
the turkey who won't stop following me!
对，我看见你了，你这个怪胎
Yeah, I see you, you weirdo.
对了，我听凯蒂说，我们明天就要走了...
Anyway, I heard Katie say we're leaving tomorrow, and...
需不需要我，回避一下?
You want me to, uh... you want me to go?
这是我们的日常活动
No. Just what we do out here.
你要一起来吗?
You want to join me?
好啊，太好了
Uh, yeah. Okay. Cool.
准备好了吗?
You ready to try?
气息往下，肚子使劲
Come on, kid. Deeper. Deep from your gut.
好的，我懂，我懂
Right. O-Okay, got it.
很不错嘛
There you go.
哇哦
Wow.
大家上车吧
All right, come on, guys.
好的
All right.
-我帅不帅? - 麦克，好酷
- Huh? What do you think? - Max, so cool.
麦克，麦克去哪了?
Hey, where-where'd Max go?
谁放进车里一个又帅又酷的小牛仔?
And who let this super cool cowboy in the car?
再见，谢普叔叔
Bye, Uncle Shep.
再见了，下次见
Good-bye, now. So long.
再见鲁叔!
Bye, Rooster!
谢谢鲁叔!
And thank you!
再见
B-Bye.
你少管我闲事，火鸡
Mind your business, turkey.
我就伤感一小会
I'm-I'm... I'm having a moment.
好吧，伤感完了
Okay, moment's over.
好好睡，宝贝
There we go, buddy.
还是回家好
Good to be home.
特别好
So good.
- 嘘! - 你才嘘
- Shh! - You shh.
嘘
Shush!
是小白
Huh? Snowball?
晚上好...
Oh, hey, what, uh...
嘿，小狗狗
Hey, Tiny Dog.
我说你怎么会带着一只老虎出现在我家?
What are you doing with a tiger in my apartment?
你不是去旅行了吗，怎么这么快就回来了?
Well, what are you doing home from your trip so soon, hmm?
互相指责的话谁都会
I mean, as long as we pointing fingers.
我们没有时间了
Hey, hey, hey. We don't have time for this.
在马戏团的狼找到这里来之前，把小虎藏起来
We are trying to hide Hu before the circus wolves get here.
马戏团的狼?
Circus wolves?
你不在我也有精彩的日子要过
You do know I have a life when you're not around, right, TD?
- 对但是... - 小白队长
- Yeah, okay, but... - Captain Snowball.
- 他们来了 -什么?
- They're here. - What?
狼群
Wolves.
哦不不不不不
Oh, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no.
糟了，他们会吃了我们的，小虎
Oh, no, they gonna kill us, Hu.
完了
Oh, this is bad.
至少我们能死在一起
Well, at least we die together.
你振作点，小家伙
Keep it together, boy.
好吧好吧
Okay. Okay.
我们得想办法，黛西
We need a plan. Daisy?
把小虎藏在屋顶上
Let's hide Hu on the roof.
小狗狗，你要去哪啊?
Tiny Dog, where are you going?
这个我也不确定...
Yeah, I'm-I'm not sure, but I guess I'm gonna...
不过我应该努力像鲁叔那样
gonna try and find my inner Rooster.
什么?
What?
别怕，别怕，别怕
Okay. Okay. Okay.
你这个胆小鬼
Puny little coward.
快上来小虎
Hurry up, Hu.
行了，把他藏到...
All right, let's hide him in the...
原来是这么个小东西
Oh. Oh, it's just this weird little guy.
我劝你从哪来回哪去，小猴子
Why don't you just go back to wherever you belong, Bonzo,
我可不想...
because I don't want to... Ow!
快跑，小虎
Run, Hu.
可爱的小狗，我喜欢你
Oh, pretty little dog, I like you.
不如你来我的马戏团给我当一发炮弹吧
You will join my circus as a cannonball.
不长记性的坏东西
Mongrel doesn't learn.
你这只傻老虎!
Stupid tiger!
赶紧走!
Pathetic. Let's go!
我们还得赶火车呢
We have a train to catch.
噢
Ow!
黛西 小虎
Daisy! Hu!
真是的
What...
他们俩在卡车里
They are in a truck.
我们怎么办呢，小狗狗?
What are we gonna do, TD?
呜呼
Whoo-hoo!
哇哦
Whoa!
大家注意
Attention.
这里是小白队长
This is Captain Snowball.
我和小狗狗需要立刻支援
Me and Tiny Dog need backup.
啾啾收到信息了，完毕
We read you loud and clear. Over.
我们正前往我马戏团
We are headed to the circus.
事情很紧急，完毕
This is urgent. Over.
收到了
Copy that.
小蜜蜂，妈妈要出发去救爸爸了
Busy Bee, Mommy's got to go save Daddy.
第二次
Again.
听着，跟我一起来!
Cats, let's do this!
# Rumor spreadin' round #
# In that Texas town #
# About that shack outside La Grange #
小宝贝们饿了吗
Are my babies hungry?
# And you know what I'm talkin' about #
吃这么快
Oh, dear.
# Have mercy #
# A-how, how, how, how #
# A-heh, a-how, how, how. #
干什么!
Whoa!
系好安全带
Buckle up, everyone.
坚持住麦克
Hang on, Max.
我们来了
We're coming.
开快点!
Floor it!
快点，小丑们!
Hurry up, you clowns!
给我走!
Let's go, let's go!
见识我的新玩具吧
Sergei have new toy.
接下来的训练会让你很好玩的
Training is going to be a lot more fun.
差不多了，咱们现在该出发了
All right, let's get this show on the tracks.
小白!
Snowball!
快点跳!
Come on, jump!
朋友们，你们在哪?
Guys, what's your location?
他们在火车上，正在往北
They're on a train headed northbound.
收到了，馒头，马上就到
- Over. - Roger that, Norman.
赶快转弯
We're on it. Go right here.
你退后，小狗
You hang back, TD.
这个任务就交给小白队长...
Captain Snowball is on the ca...
小白!
Snowball!
我没事
I'm fine.
那你，能不能
Yeah, can, uh... can you, uh,
想办法上来...?
find a way to get back up here, or is there...?
怎么...?
What the...?
小狗狗
Tiny Dog.
什么声音? 你好?
What was that? Hello?
黛西!
Daisy!
小白!
Snowball!
谢天谢地
Oh, thank goodness.
快把我弄出来，我卡住了
Get me out of here. I'm stuck.
好的
Okay, okay, look... Huh?
吃我一拳
Body blow.
把手举起来投降吧，小猴子
This ends now, monkey.
你还在吗蠢猴子
You still there, monkey? Huh?
来了
Oh, no! He's here! He's here!
还拿着火!
And on fire!
把我弄出去!
Hey! Get me out of here!
小白，灭掉引信!
Snowball, the fuse!
我来了
I got it. I got it.
再见吧，蠢猴子!
Say good-bye, monkey!
好啊小狗
All right, doggy.
有种过来
Bring it.
小狗狗!
Tiny Dog!
给我滚开!
Get away! Get off me!
给我滚开
Go away!
放开我!
My God!
跟我来
Come on.
站住!
Stop!
你哪都别想去
You are going nowhere.
我已经受够了
I've had enough.
游戏到此结束
This ends here and now.
# Oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh, oh... #
嘿，麦克
Hi, Max.
啾啾
Gidget.
那个是坏蛋吧?
Uh, that was a bad guy, right?
是的
Yes.
行了
Whoa. Okay, all right, all right,
行了行了
all right, all right, all right, all right.
我们成功了!
- We did it! - Whoo!
- 太棒啦! - 真是太好了!
- Awesome! - Yay! - This is so good!
# I can feel the sun shining #
# I can see the stars aligning... #
好吧，就这样，生活回归正常
Okay, so things got back to normal.
# I can feel my heart beating... #
基本正常
I mean, mostly.
俗话说得好:
You know what they say:
上天关上一扇门,
When life closes a door,
就会为你打开猫咪的窗户
it opens a cat lady's window.
真是奶奶的乖猫猫
That's a good kitty.
因为什么都会改变
Because everything changes.
早上好，小白
Good morning, Snowball.
没有什么能永远不变
Nothing stays the same for long.
当你习惯之后
The minute you're used to something,
你就会想, "哦，生活就是这样"
the minute you think, "Oh, this is how life is,"
- 生活总是那么让你惊喜
- life finds a way of surprising you. - Aw.
这怎么回事?
Hey, man, what is going on?
这怎么...
What? This is...
太帅啦!
awesome! Wow!
来吧宝贝
Come on, buddy.
一定很好玩的
- This is gonna be fun. - Whoo-hoo!
你不知道未来会发生什么
You never know what life is gonna throw at you.
但是你有两个选择
And you have two choices:
要么逃避
run from it...
Boo!
要么勇敢面对
...or run at it.
- # The sun keep blinding me # - # Whoo #
# I don't know what you've been told... #
这一天来了
It's a big day.
从今天起，生活会天翻地覆
And from this point on, nothing is gonna be the same.
哇哦
Wow.
- # Just keep that smile upon your face # - Hi.
我会勇敢面对
But I'm gonna be brave.
# 'Cause everything's gonna be okay... #
我也会帮利安勇敢面对
And I'm gonna help Liam be brave.
因为他是我的小孩
Because he's my kid,
我想让他看遍世界
and I want him to see the world.
这个庞大，可怕，又神奇的世界
The big, scary, incredible world.
这是你的小房间  就在那边
Okay, there's your cubby. Right over there.
你还好吧?
Are you okay?
很好
Yeah.
我很好
I'm good.
# It's gonna be a lovely day... #
# L-L-L-L-Lovely... #
等等
Wait.
我的狗狗
My doggies.
永远爱你
Always.
再见，爸爸妈妈
Bye-bye, Mama and Dada.
# Just keep that smile upon your face #
# 'Cause everything's gonna be okay #
# Just sing along with it #
# Oh, I know somebody love me #
# Someone be trying to hug me #
# Road is getting bumpy #
# Hey, but it's gonna be a lovely day #
# Oh, yeah, I know you feeling lonely #
# Someone be trying to hold me #
# You can't be acting grumpy #
# It's gonna be a lovely day #
# Oh, I know somebody love me #
# Someone be trying to hug me #
# Road is getting bumpy #
# Hey, but it's gonna be a lovely day #
# Oh, yeah, I know you feeling lonely #
# Someone be trying to hold me #
# You can't be acting grumpy #
# It's gonna be a lovely day #
# Hey, l-l-l-l-lovely #
# L-L-L-L-Lovely #
# Oh, it's gonna be a lovely day #
# Oh, l-l-l-l-lovely #
- # L-L-L-L-Lovely # - # L-L-L-L-Lovely #
# L-L-L-L-Lovely #
# Ooh, it's gonna be a lovely day. #
再见  小白   再见  熊先生
Bye, Snowball. Bye, Mr. Bear.
# Panda #
# Panda, panda, panda, panda #
# Panda, listen, hey #
# I got broads in Atlanta #
# Twisting rope, drinking Fanta #
# Credit cards and the scammers #
# Hittin' off licks in the bando #
# Black X6, Phantom #
# Wait and see, looking like a panda #
# Panda, panda, panda, panda #
# Listen #
# Hundred scammers, Black X6, Phantom #
# Wait and see, Panda #
# Pockets swole, Danny #
# Selling bar, candy #
# Man, I'm the macho like Randy... #
小白  我回来啦
Snowball, I'm back.
# Panda, panda, panda, panda, panda. #
好吧，伤感完了
Okay, moment's over.